# JURANDI CARVALHO



jurandi.carvalho@outlook.com



+55 61 98506 3808



linkedin.com/in/jurandi-carvalho-85960216a



https://jcarvalhooak.github.io/

### Summary

CLICK HERE TO SEE MY COMPLETE RESUME:

https://jcarvalhooak.github.io/

I am a Post Graduate in Software Engineering, with a degree in Systems Analysis and Development and a specialization in NETWORKS, SPRING, and REACT.

I Participated in projects and systems development for the Brazilian government, such as SISBIB for PRODASEN (Federal Senate 2000 - 2005), SISBACEN for DEINF (Central Bank of Brazil 2005 - 2009), ANUNCIADOR for CEL190 (Caixa Econômica Federal 2021) among others.

### Specializations in:

Android STUDIO, SPRING, REACT, JPA, AND HIBERNATE

#### Knowledge:

UML - ASTA and SQLiteStudio Front - HTML, PHP, JS, TS, REACT Back - JAVA DB - Firebase, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

#### Specific skills in:

Agile Methodologies, Software Quality, Business Intelligence, Clean Code, Software Testing, Leadership and People Management, Strategic Business Communication, Design Patterns, Usability Engineering, Configuration Management, Architecture and Data Model, Analysis and Requirements Specification, Team Project Management with Scrum.

# **Experience**



### **Development Analyst**

Mastertecnologia

Jun 2013 - Present (8 years 11 months +)

My duties, among others, are:

I am responsible for gathering requirements,

prototyping and data modeling,

operational standards, routines, safety criteria

functionalities, applicability tests and expected results, preparation and training of teams with PDCA, and continuous improvement cycles with agile development, based on SCRUM.

We provide consulting services to other companies, in the aforementioned aspects, as well as surveys of needs and improvements, design and creation of systems, and consulting in Networks, network security, and Telecommunications.

In addition to the analysis work, I do development in the following areas:

Android Application Development using JAVA 11, Firebase, SQLite, Postgress, and ASTAH.

Website development for WEB in PHP, HTML, REACT, JS and TS.

WEB development, with JAVA, SPRING, JPA, HIBERNATE, SQL.

Specific knowledge used:

Android, Firebase, Docker, Postgres,

MVVM architecture

Consumption of REST APIs and Use of Websockets.

Spring framework, Java APIs and libraries, Java EE, Interface improvements, JUnit unit testing skills, STS, coding skills, and knowledge of design patterns.

Version control (Git)

## NETWORK AND DATA COMMUNICATION ANALYST

CELFINET (BRAZIL) - Consultancy in telecommunications.

Jun 2011 - Mar 2013 (1 year 10 months)

I performed analysis, development, and implementation of computer systems, as well as system project management, meeting standards and quality standards, usability, integrity, and information security.

# Entrepreneur and technology and networking consultant

Master Computers and Technology Consulting

Jul 2008 - Dec 2011 (3 years 6 months)

Master Computers and Technology Consulting

A company created and directed by me, with a team of more than thirteen employees, including HR, microcomputer technicians, salespeople, and Systems Analysts, we provide services and varied inputs for the creation of systems, network security, technology, and automation implementations, consulting, Business Intelligence and Standards of technological frameworks for companies and individuals.

# System programmer

DEINF/BACEN - Department of IT in the Central Bank of Brazil

Oct 2005 - Jun 2009 (3 years 9 months)

System development and service to SISBACEN users.

Base technology: Java SE 6

User registration and control system, the Central Bank Information System (Sisbacen) is the set of information technology systems and resources to support and conduct processes. The Central Bank Information System organizes financial data, bringing transparency and security to institutions and individuals, through this system linked to the Central Bank, data on financial and banking operations are collected, recorded, and stored. carried out in Brazil, aiming at the centralization of financial information.

# JUNIOR DEVELOPER

PRODASEN - Data Processing of the Federal Senate of the Brazil

Jan 2000 - Sep 2005 (5 years 9 months)

Development of SISBIB - Federal Senate Library System.

Base technologies: J2SE 1.4, and SQL.

Participation in the Project plan, conceptual model (UML), coding, and maintenance of the system that had user registration, collection control, loan flow, entries, exits, and special functions such as rare works and access controlled by user level.

### **Education**



### Innovation Center VincIT - UNICIV - Brazil

Lato Sensu PostgraduateSoftware Engineering with an Emphasis on Quality and Software TestingA+, Software Engineering with an Emphasis on Quality and Software **Testing** 

Nov 2019 - Apr 2021

Study skills:

Agile Methodologies

Software quality

business intelligence

Source Code Quality (Clean Code)

Software Testing

Leadership and People Management

Strategic Business Communication

**Design Patterns** 

**Usability Engineering** 

Configuration Management, Version and Change Control Architecture and Alternative Data Model -NOSQL/ DATA WAREHOUSE / DATA MINING

Requirements Analysis and Specification, Project Management with Scrum.



#### FAP

GraduationAnalysis and systems development, Computer Systems Analysis/Analyst Jul 2016 - Dec 2018

With a lot of work, a lot of dedication, and continuous study, I acquired and improved my skills, today I can carry out the project of a system until it is delivered for use. Basically, as an Analyst I can:

Maintain existing systems and repair them as needed.

Define the requirements and functionalities of a system to be developed.

Develop, test, and implement systems based on the definition of requirements and resources.

Develop system documentation. In the documentation, I can include tutorials, user manuals, maintenance routines, and standards for new versions.

Customer service and support. Because I have technical knowledge, as an analyst, I guide the user on how to use the system and also identify bugs based on customer complaints.

Identify, map, and analyze technological options and tools in the market to be acquired by a company.

### **Licenses & Certifications**



Software Engineering with Emphasis on Quality and Software Testing - Centro de

Inovação VincIT - UNICIV

f21f8a48480bb1e76f6606000b6862a8



# Engenharia de Software com Ênfase em Qualidade e Teste de Software - Centro

de Inovação VincIT - UNICIV

f21f8a48480bb1e76f6606000b6862a8

### **Skills**

Networking • Supervisory Skills • Application Programming Interfaces • Troubleshooting • Telecommunications Management • People Management • Computer Network Operations • Software Development • Gestão de projetos • Liderança de equipe